ulyssesapp.com 2019-07-08

# Ulysses › App Privacy Policy

_Notice: This privacy policy only applies to our homepage and the[Styles & Themes website](https://styles.ulysses.app/).  
If you are looking for the privacy policy of our app, please follow this link_.

## Introduction

At Ulysses, we respect your privacy. We believe that the less we know about you, the better; that is why we aim to limit the information we collect to the minimum necessary. The purpose of this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is to inform you in detail what personally identifiable information or personal information we collect from you when you use our website, how we use such information, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to review and correct, the information.

We reserve the right to change this policy, which we will do through online posting. We use your data solely to provide you with services in which you enroll.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, the terms “Ulysses”, “we,” “us” and “our” refer to the company Ulysses GmbH & Co. KG; the term “website” refer to the Ulysses website and related services; and “you” refers to you, as a user of the website as applicable.

## Who We Are

Ulysses GmbH & Co. KG is a German company located in Brockhausstraße 88, 04229 Leipzig. We comply with the European law for Data Protection (“GDPR”).

## What Information We Collect and How We Use It

We collect solely information that is necessary to provide you with our services and to improve our website. We do not share these data with third party services (e.g., Google or Facebook) for the purpose of advertising.

**Styles & Themes Account Information.** To allow the users of our app to exchange Ulysses styles and themes, we offer a website called Styles & Themes. If you want to upload a style or a theme on this website, you need to create an account. To manage your Styles & Themes account, we store the email address or social media handle you used for sign-in, as well as associated credentials like passwords or authentication tokens. – Legal basis Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR

**Website Analytics (Optional).** To improve our website, we use the web analytics software Matomo to collect pseudonymized data about the time of your visit, the pages you visit, as well as the device and browser you are using. – Legal basis Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR

**Email Newsletter Subscription (Optional).** To inform you about new features, releases and blog posts, we offer a newsletter for which you can subscribe with your email address.

We use Campaign Monitor to manage our newsletter and other email lists. Campaign Monitor provides us with data concerning your email activity, that is, the place, date and time where and when you open our messages, the device type you are using, and your interactions with our messages such as clicking a link.

You can unsubscribe from our newsletter by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided at the end of the newsletter. If you don’t want us to track your email activity, you can click the preferences link at the end of the newsletter. It will take you to your newsletter preferences, where you can opt out from email activity tracking. You can also email [help@ulysses.app](mailto:help@ulysses.app) to update or unsubscribe your email address, to request that we delete your email address, or that we stop tracking your email activity. – Legal basis Art. 6(1)(a+f) GDPR

**Cookies.** We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * **Website Analytics** to identify you as a visitor.
  * **Website Analytics Consent** to store your consent regarding the analytics tracking.
  * **Styles & Themes Authentication** to check your login status.

## Where We Store Your Data

**Style & Themes Content and Account information.** Your Styles & Themes content is stored on our servers hosted by Hetzner and can be viewed and downloaded on the Styles & Themes website. If you would like to delete your account you can go to your profile settings and press the „Delete Account“ button.

**Website Analytics (Optional).** The usage data and device information are stored with a pseudonymized cookie ID on our own servers hosted by Melting Mind. If you want us to delete all tracked data, please send a message to [help@ulysses.app](mailto:help@ulysses.app).

**Customer Support Emails.** For customer support and email services, we use Front as our help desk software. This means that every email you send to us will be stored at Front. Additionally, we are legally required to archive all email traffic for ten years. This is done by our server hosting company Melting Mind. We do not have direct access to the created backups.

## How Long We Store Your Data For

We store your data for as long as German law requires, or as is necessary for the fulfillment or the initiation of a contract, or as long as we claim legitimate interests. After the expiration of that period, the corresponding data is routinely deleted or completely anonymized. We have detailed some of the deletion periods under “Where We Store Your Data”. Statistical and diagnostic data is generally never deleted.

We clarify that the provision of personal data is partly required by law (e.g., tax regulations) or can result from contractual provisions (e.g., information on the contractual partner).

## Data Processors

Depending on the usage of our services your personal data might be processed by the following services:

### Campaign Monitor

Email marketing service provided by Campaign Monitor Pty Limited, Australia.

**Personal Data:** Email address and tracking data  
**Country of Data Processing:** USA or Australia

### Front

Help desk software provided by FrontApp, Inc. 

**Personal Data:** Support emails   
**Country of Data Processing:** USA

### Melting Mind

Email and web server hosting company.

**Personal Data:** Email traffic   
**Country of Data Processing:** Germany

### Hetzner

Web server hosting company.

**Personal Data:** Styles & Themes account data   
**Country of Data Processing:** Germany

**Right to Access.** You can request Ulysses to provide you with information on how we collect, use, and store your personal information, and to provide you with a copy of your personal information we store.

**Right of Rectification.** You can request that we correct inaccurate information about you.

**Right to Delete.** You can request that we delete information collected about you, given that we are not required by law to preserve it, that it is not necessary for contract fulfillment, and that we can still identify your records.

**Right to Object.** You can object to the processing of your information in certain cases, as well as request that Ulysses does not use your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

**Right to Data Portability.** If requested, we will provide you all data under our control in common, machine-readable formats. If requested, we will provide you with instructions to obtain your data, in cases where we do not have direct access.

If you have any questions regarding your personal data as well as your privacy rights, please contact

Ulysses GmbH & Co. KG   
Data Protection Officer   
Brockhausstraße 88   
04229 Leipzig   
Germany 

Email: [privacy@ulysses.app](mailto:privacy@ulysses.app)

## Responsible Body for Data Privacy

Responsible body for the processing of personal data within the meaning of the law. Art. 4 (7) GDPR:

Ulysses GmbH & Co. KG   
Brockhausstraße 88   
04229 Leipzig   
Germany 

Email: [mail@ulysses.app](mailto:mail@ulysses.app)

We may use your contact information to communicate with you about our product, diagnostic data and error reports, provide support, and send you other information such as product updates and announcements. You can opt out of news and announcements by unsubscribing from our newsletter.

## Breach Notification

If the confidentiality of customer data is breached, we recognize our responsibility to our customers and to the public to disclose the nature of the risk and provide a transparent account of the events without undue delay. At a bare minimum, we must inform the applicable supervisory authorities as required by law and regulation.

## Consent for Underage Enrollment

Those under the age of 16 may not use the services without the consent or authorization of their parent or legal custodian.

## Updates to Our Privacy Policy

At our discretion, we may make changes to this Policy and note the date of the last revision. You should check here frequently if you need to know of updates to our Privacy Policy. We maintain the right to inform you of substantive changes via email. Previous versions of this page will be made available.

## Glossary

### Ulysses

Ulysses (or sometimes “we”, “us” or “our”) refers to the company Ulysses GmbH & Co. KG.

### Pseudonymization

Pseudonymization is the processing of personal data in such a manner that the personal data can no longer be attributed to an identified or identifiable natural person without the use of additional information, provided that such additional information is kept separately and is subject to technical and organizational measures to ensure that the personal data are not attributed to an identified or identifiable natural person.

_Last updated: March 18, 2019_
